# JAMES DE JESUS

2300 Broadway #2, Oakland CA, 94612 | me@jamesdejesus.com

# **SUMMARY**

An experienced technologist, I work with teams to develop innovative web and mobile solutions for small businesses to Fortune 500 companies. I got my start as a designer which helps me to bridge the gap between creative, user experience and technology. As leader at the department level, I mentor engineers and technical managers in developing their individual skills and increasing the overall capability of the department. I continue to write both front-end and backend (Python) code and I'm very comfortable working with a variety of technical stacks in an agile environment.

# **SKILLS & TECHNOLOGIES**

Department leadership, Technical project management with Agile methodologies, resource management, personnel management and mentorship, client facing, interaction design

Languages: HTML, CSS, JS/ES6, PHP, Python

**Libraries and Frameworks:** jQuery, React, Angular, SASS/SCSS, Handlebars, ejs, Jade, Nunjucks, Bootstrap

**Server-side technologies:** Node.js, Laravel, Drupal, Django

**Automation and Provisioning:** Gulp, Grunt, Ansible

**Cloud Infrastructure:** AWS, Heroku, Digital Ocean, Codeship, CircleCl

# SELECTED CLIENTS

EA, Tesla Motors, Genentech, Blu Homes, Facebook, Hennessy, Google, Nike Jordan, Anheuser Busch, Levi's, Visa, Google+, Audi, Gap, Old Navy, Verizon, Target, Red Bull, Leapfrog and McDonalds

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## Odopod

2014 - present Technical Director

- Oversee the technical discipline, helping to evolve the tools, technologies and practices within the group
- Develop and maintain Python/Django website backends.
- Setup and maintain internal and client website environments.
- · Mentor developers and guide their career growth
- Work with client stakeholders to help define a project and help to guide it to completion
- Collaborate with other discipline leads to improve communication, process and practices between disciplines
- Assist in the new business process in the creation of pitch decks and presentation delivery
- Participate in both on and off site recruiting activities for the Technology department
- Manage technical aspects of client projects including task creation and allocation, scrum leadership and code reviews

## **AKQA San Francisco**

2010 - 2014

Director of Creative Research & Development and Interim Director of Technology

- Own the vision and direction of the Creative Research & Development discipline
- Guide professional growth of managers and developers on the team
- Collaborate with other disciplines to continually improve the project process and quality of deliverables
- · Determine compensation levels for all members of the team
- Resolve any discipline or interpersonal issues that may arise on the team.
- · Assist in creative concepting
- Handle developer resource allocation on all projects
- Manage full-stack development projects (Python, Java, .Net. Rails)
- Work with internal and external recruiting personnel to maintain candidate pipeline for the team.
- Determine scope and feasibility for upcoming projects
- Raise the profile of the department through public speaking and outreach at universities and ad/creative schools

2009 - 2010

Associate Director of Creative Research & Development

- Own the vision and direction of the Creative Research & Development discipline
- Mentor front-end managers and developers
- Manage front-end development projects
- · Assist with creative concepting
- · Determine scope and feasibility for upcoming projects

## 2008 - 2009 Technical Manager

- Manage teams developing front-end applications
- · Assist in creative concepting
- Mentor junior developers
- Assist with scope and feasibility checks

2006 - 2008

Senior Creative Developer

- Architect and develop front-end applications
- · Assist in creative concepting
- Lead development teams
- · Mentor junior developers

#### **EVB**

2005 - 2006

Interactive Developer

Develop Actionscript and HTML/CSS/JS applications

#### **Allen Interactions**

2004 - 2005

Contract Flash Developer

Develop Flash-based e-learning applications

### Fly Design Inc.

2003 - 2006

Contract Flash Designer and Developer

Design, animate and develop Actionscript experiences

## **Dunn Solutions Group / Streams**

1997 - 2004

Senior Designer and Interactive Media Developer

- Design and develop interactive applications in Actionscript, Director, PHP and HTML/CSS/|S
- Created SCORM compliant e-learning applications
- Develop online platform and shooter games in Director / Lingo
- Lead development teams
- Mentor junior developers
- Consulted on experience design and user flow

## **Cyberworks Studios**

1998 - 1998

Designer

- Develop CD-ROM applications in Director
- Create web sites in HTML/JS

# **Paradigm Productions**

1997 - 1998 Designer

- Design advertisements for print catalog
- Develop CD-ROM applications in Director
- Create web sites in HTML/JS

# **EDUCATION**

Northern Illinois University BFA, Design - Electronic Media 1993 - 1997